NZ Citizen
021 022 58062
thiffanyjun@hotmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub

# **Tiffany Wang**

#### About me

Kia ora, I'm Tiff! I'm a **full-stack software developer** with an education and digital design background. I bring a huge amount of skills from my 7-year teaching experience, particularly my ability to emphasise, communicate, plan, and work in a team. My experience in web design also adds an extra layer of creativity to my software development work.

I fell in love with coding when I encountered HTML and CSS during a Web Design course. I heard from tech friends that Javascript is much harder which may deter me. It seems not true as after following a couple of Javascript tutorial videos, I can't wait to learn even more! Being able to learn new things every day, engage in constant problem-solving, and know that I can build remarkable software to solve real-world problems truly motivates me.

I'm currently working on building my tech portfolio and learning Microsoft Azure Foundation. I'm excited about the endless possibilities in the tech world and look forward to collaborating with people to create impactful things.

When I'm not working, I enjoy cooking, hitting the gym, practicing hip-hop dance, and pampering my cat with tummy rubs.

## **Experience**

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

## Full-stack Software Developer

Dev Academy Aotearoa · Apprenticeship

- This was a 15-week, 800-hour full immersion software development bootcamp that mimics the real-world Agile development team with multiple projects that focus on both web development and people skills.
- Tech stack includes HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Knex, SQLite3, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, and GitHub.
- In my final project, <u>Tiff's Donuts</u>, I acted as the Product Owner with five other team members where we developed a web application for users to create 3D donuts. The website includes rendering 3D models, interactions and scrolling effects using threeJS and React. During this intensive 7-day project, I had the opportunity to take the lead in introducing and implementing **React Three Fiber**, a technology not covered in our bootcamp. This experience was truly valuable as it showcased our team's dedication to collaborative problem-solving and our ability to adapt and learn on the fly.

Aug 2022- Jun 2023

## Freelance Web Designer

Freelance

- Provided logo design and UI/UX design for several volunteer-driven side projects including web interface design and Webflow building. Feel free to check my <u>design wonderland</u>.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Adobe Creative Suites, prototyping and design thinking skills.

#### Nov 2021- Jun 2023

#### Centre Administrator

Tots on Triton Childcare

- Demonstrated excellent customer service and communication skills.
- Streamlined administrative workflow, resulting in a 30% reduction in task time and significant productivity and cost savings.
- Served as the go-to tech support for teachers encountering issues with their computers and printers.
- Maintained well-organised records and documents that helped the service pass the Education Office Review.

Nov 2019- Nov 2021

### Career Break and Parental Leave

Multiple Ventures

• I had my pregnancy and parental leave while exploring the possibilities of career change including studying and completing a Graduate Diploma of Professional Accounting and Foundation Level Certified Tester from ASTQB.

Apr 2017- Nov 2019

#### Head Teacher

New Shoots Childcare Centre

- Took on a leadership role in guiding the team to deliver high-quality education and care for children.
- Facilitated collaborative discussions to develop tailored strategies that successfully transformed the classroom into the most calm and organised one.
- Designed an intuitive program planning board that effectively improved the consistency of centre program planning.
- Fostered distributed leadership and encouraged every team member to contribute their expertise to delivering quality services as a team.

Feb 2013- Apr 2017

## Registered Teacher

**Evolve Education Group** 

- Engaged in close collaboration with my team of educators to ensure the best outcomes for children.
- Consistently recognised by colleagues and parents for my ability to identify children's needs, demonstrating strong observational and empathy skills.
- Actively participated in reflective teaching sessions, fostering a culture of continuous improvement and learning.

#### Education

Web Development Training Scheme | Level 6

Dev Academy Aotearoa | 2023

Diploma in Digital Design (Web and Graphic Design)

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation | 2022 - 2023

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting (Average A)

Auckland University of Technology | 2021-2022

Bachelor of Teaching

New Zealand Tertiary College | 2012 - 2014

#### References

Available on request